wondering how to use employee benefits
don't know how to use employee benefits
to know more watch this video till end
hello and welcome back to our YouTube
channel
today we'll be discussing about employee
benefits exactly what they are and how
to utilize them so what are employee
benefits these are any form of perks
that an employer receives in addition to
his or her salary the most common type
of employee benefits include medical
disability and life insurances so uh so
these are typically provided almost by
every employer in North America and they
may play a very important role when a
candidate is making a decision about
accepting a job offer or not
so here on the screen you can see the
list of uh most popular insurance and
benefits provider in Canada
as mentioned earlier one of the most
common benefits that is provided uh is
the medical insurance so medical
insurance is broadly bifurcated under
three sections that is Health dental and
vision
Dental typically covers the services
listed here as well as some others
depending on the insurance provider
uh the next one is a vision which covers
your eye exams glasses contact lenses
and even prescription sunglasses
so please do check your benefits to
understand what all services are covered
under your plans
for example uh under Vision your eye
exams are covered
insurance providers
and last but not the least Health Plan
includes all the other services which
are not covered under the dental and
vision plan but are very important for
your own well-being so typically such as
typically massage therapy speech therapy
physiotherapy chiropractor and
psychologist these all services fall
under the health plan
uh depending on your employer and the
benefits provider you can add your
family members or dependents to be
covered under your medical insurance
plan so if uh you have to you may have
to check with your employer how much
extra premium you will have to pay uh
per month or per pay period in case you
need to add an independent uh to your
medical insurance plan
and most of the benefits get renewed
yearly so make sure to utilize them
before the labs by December end
to check your maximum coverage and the
types of services that are covered under
your plan simply log into your account
on the insurer's website and check under
the coverage section you can find all
the details there including what all
services are covered and most of the
popular insurance providers have mobile
applications as well so that you can
check uh the details over the phone
so this is how the Manulife mobile
application looks like you can log in
you can check for the dependent
coverages or coverages for yourself
there are n number of services available
in different areas like vision
Health dental
so you can go ahead and check the
maximum
coverage amount
or you can check how much you have
exhausted so far
so for dental there are various Services
which you can opt for
for chiropractor
you can check the service balance
same for the massage therapy
to utilize that massage therapy coverage
you can go to the benefits card and
download it
check the claims
it will show you the record of
all the claims
here you can check
nearby to your location
what are the different types of
providers available
in your neighborhood
so you can
if you want to submit a new claim then
you can do it
You by clicking on a new claim and then
you can submit the claim
you heard some of the tips and
suggestions which we would like to share
based on our experience tip number one
if you and your spouse have individual
benefit coverages then make sure you add
each other in your plans by doing this
you won't end up paying anything uh from
your own pocket also if you have
children then make sure you add them in
both of your plans for example if your
plan just covers 90 percent of the
service expense for a single session of
massage then you can claim the other 10
percent in your spouse's plan
tip number two most of the people
including us wait until December uh to
use their benefits but don't make that
mistake try to spread out the
appointments over the calendar year
because it's very difficult to get the
appointments 11th hour we had tough time
scheduling all these appointments tip
number three ensure with your service
providers how much each service would
cost you and plan out for future visits
accordingly also check the amount that
you have exhausted so far and how much
can be utilized later on
up there
tip number four call and look for the
clinics or service providers who
directly builds the insurer to avoid
last minute hassle of submitting all the
claims by yourself
tip number five keep your benefit and
health card handy at the time of at
least the first appointment
so this was a short video about the
benefit plans and how to utilize them
thanks for watching and hope you find
this video useful and stay tuned for our
next videos
bye bye
[Music]